Austin Jones

Austin.t.jones.21@utexas.edu · (713) 884-0500 · linkedin.com/in/austinjones19

EDUCATION

The University of Texas at AustinBachelor of Science in Mathematics

May 2024

Overall GPA: 3.93

Certificates: Elements of Computing, Applied Statistical Modeling

RELEVANT COURSEWORK

Elements of Data Visualization – Spring 2022

- Used Google Collab and Altair to visualize data with Python
- Created final project analyzing video game speed runs for various popular video games

Elements of Data Science - Fall 2022

- Learned how to process, clean, tidy, and join datasets in R
- Learned visualization principles and how to apply them with ggplot2 in R
- Learned dimension reduction, clustering, classification metrics, and regression methods in R
- Created two projects analyzing relationships between COVID-19 levels and Amazon stock prices

SUMMARY

Hard-working 3rd year Mathematics student with a passion for leveraging data to produce real-world insights. Experience working in teams with a preference for collaborative, forward-looking companies that are innovating in the data visualization and analysis spaces.

EXPERIENCE

UT TIDES - Research Assistant; Austin, Texas

May 2022 - Present

- Performed data preprocessing by cleaning Excel sheets and CSVs, inputting missing values and deriving new fields
- Created dashboard in Tableau to visualize data
- Strategized with boss weekly to discuss next steps for current and future projects
- Created tables from Excel sheets to analyze trends regarding multiple variables for various groups

Varsity Tutors - Mathematics Tutor; Virtual

May 2021 - August 2021

- Tutored students in 10 mathematics subjects, took certification tests for each subject tutored
- Received 5-star average tutor rating from multiple client reviews
- Achieved >5% grade or score increase for clients by developing personalized tutoring plans for clients and utilizing interactive learning techniques

Lonestar Pool Management - Lifeguard, Swim Instructor; Cypress, TX

May 2019 - August 2020

- Ensured safety of patrons on waterslide, diving board, and in lazy river at Towne Lake Waterpark
- Performed check-in duties for residents and guests, cleaned pools and bathrooms, set up/tore down equipment, checked pool chemicals to ensure safe levels, and inventoried furniture, safety equipment and lost and found items
- Instructed children in introductory swimming techniques including floating, exhaling underwater, diving for pool toys, and basic stroke techniques

LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE AND ACTIVITIES

Longhorn Swim Club - President (Summer 2022 – Present)

Fall 2021 - Present

- Authored monthly newsletters with the officer team to discuss club dues, meets, practice schedules, socials, etc.
- Met weekly with officer team to discuss plans for coming weeks including finances, meet transportation, socials, and other strategic planning
- Created training regime for practices, lead practices while swimming, provided transportation to meets and socials
- Organized transportation, relays, and finances for meets, and general finances, socials, and volunteer opportunities

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Skills: Experience with SQL, proficient in Python, R, Excel, Tableau and Java, comfort with Windows and Common Programs

Certifications: CITI Human Subjects Research Training, LinkedIn Learning Data Visualization: Storytelling, LinkedIn Learning Quick Start Guide to SQL, LinkedIn Learning SQL Queries Made Easy, Microsoft Excel, Word, PowerPoint, and Access

Interests: Data Analytics, Coding, Grunge and Alternative Rock, Rock Climbing, Swimming

Work Eligibility: Eligible to work in the U.S. with no restrictions

Honor Societies: Golden Key National Honor Society, National Society of Collegiate Scholars

Languages: Fluency in English, Basic Spanish Knowledge